

# **Sudipta Dutta**

#### MOBILE DEVELOPER

#### **PROFILE**

I am a software engineer with 11+ years of experience in Mobile development with Android, iOS and cross-platform technologies. Currently, I am part of the Reality labs division at Meta.

My interests are in technology, photography, travel, football, and astronomy.

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

#### **Address**

Berlin, Germany

#### CONTACT

- ir2pid@gmail.com
- https://ir2pid.github.io/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/ir2pid/
- https://github.com/ir2pid

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### META/FACEBOOK EUROPE GMBH(BERLIN)

Part of the Reality labs division at Meta.

#### Software engineer

VANGUARD GROUP EUROPE GMBH (BERLIN)

Jan 2022 - Mar 2022

Apr 2022 - present

Working on the architecture of a unified one-app to replace all regional Vanguard investment apps

#### Software engineer

EPAY GMBH (MUNICH)

Nov 2018 - Dec 2021

Developing, deploying and maintaining financial apps, Android, iOS and Ionic. Maintaining and creating new apps for Euronet worldwide subsidiaries and clients.

#### Software engineer

#### SKOOBE GMBH (MUNICH)

Apr 2017 - Nov 2018

Overseeing all mobile development including Android and iOS (Senior App Developer) Improving and maintaining our continuous integration and delivery platform. Working with testers, setting up automated test environments.

#### **Application Development Senior Analyst**

# ACCENTURE (FRANKFURT AM MAIN/PUNE)

Sept 2013 - Mar 2017

Collaborated with the 2nd largest bank of Germany to digitize their banking services on iOS and Android. Work on build scripts, continuous integration and delivery.

Took over the critical task of ensuring app security for the Bank's apps.

## **Mobile Engineer**

## WEBSPIDERS (KOLKATA)

Mar 2013 - Jul 2013

Worked on the iOS app and act as a point of contact for our clients.

#### **Software Engineer**

### E-FORCE (KOLKATA)

Sept 2010 - Mar 2013

Worked on the android and iOS apps. Coordination and alignment with the mobile teams and backend

### **EDUCATION**

### Masters in Business Administration(Part-time)

UNIVERSITY OF MANNHEIM

Sept2017 - Sept2019

**Masters in Computer Application** 

**B.P.P.IMT (WEST BENGAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY)** 

Aug2007 - Apr2010

**Bachelors in Computer Application** 

**B.P.P.IMT (WEST BENGAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY)** 

May2004 - Jun2007

# **SKILLS**

CI/CD ios Typescript Android Kotlin Java Flutter Ionic

#### **EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

NGO work for Abheda Foundation, to deliver educational apps for children in rural classrooms.

INITIATIVES/POSITION HELD



Samsung app of the year award 2011 for our game Find a Way Jose.